[
    {
        "question": "Absolute code can be generated for ____.",
        "options": [
            "compile-time binding",
            "load-time binding",
            "execution-time binding",
            "interrupt binding"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An address generated by a CPU is referred to as a ____.",
        "options": [
            "physical address",
            "logical address",
            "post relocation register address",
            "Memory-Management Unit (MMU) generated address"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Suppose a program is operating with execution-time binding and the physical address generated is 300. The relocation register is set to 100. What is the corresponding logical address?",
        "options": ["199", "201", "200", "300"],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The mapping of a logical address to a physical address is done in hardware by the ________.",
        "options": [
            "memory-management-unit (MMU)",
            "memory address register",
            "relocation register",
            "dynamic loading register"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "_____ is the dynamic storage-allocation algorithm which results in the smallest leftover hole in memory.",
        "options": ["First fit", "Best fit", "Worst fit", "None of the above"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "_____ is the dynamic storage-allocation algorithm which results in the largest leftover hole in memory.",
        "options": ["First fit", "Best fit", "Worst fit", "None of the above"],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider a logical address with a page size of 8 KB. How many bits must be used to represent the page offset in the logical address?",
        "options": ["10", "8", "13", "12"],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Assume a system has a TLB hit ratio of 90%. It requires 15 nanoseconds to access the TLB, and 85 nanoseconds to access main memory. What is the effective memory access time in nanoseconds for this system?",
        "options": ["108.5", "100", "22", "176.5"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the logical address 0xAEF9 (in hexadecimal) with a page size of 256 bytes, what is the page number?",
        "options": ["0xAE", "0xF9", "0xA", "0x00F9"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the logical address 0xAEF9 (in hexadecimal) with a page size of 256 bytes, what is the page offset?",
        "options": ["0xAE", "0xF9", "0xA", "0xF900"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Assume the value of the base and limit registers are 1200 and 350 respectively. Which of the following addresses is legal?",
        "options": ["355", "1200", "1551", "all of the above"],
        "answer": 1
    }
]
